David M Bry

Philadelphia PA | 908-433-0919 | linkedin.com/in/dbry23 | dbry23@gmail.com

PROFILE

Seasoned .NET developer bringing 13+ years of unique experience from a variety of industries. With a history of solving complex problems and delivering innovative solutions, I have increased sales at Traffic Safety Store 20+% year-over-year, and saved Dechert LLP over \$20,000/year. I am adaptable, open to change, and quick to learn in new situations. I possess Sherlock-like investigative skills to get to the root cause of technical issues.

Looking solely for 100% remote work to become a digital nomad (traveling while working).

SKILLS/KNOWLEDGE

Languages: C#, VB, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, PHP, Twig, PowerShell, Bash

Libraries/Frameworks: ASP.NET (MVC & Web Forms), LINQ, Entity Framework, jQuery, React, Vue.js

Other: Visual Studio, Git, GitHub, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, Grunt, npm, TFS, Microsoft SSRS, Microsoft SSIS, Grav

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Curriculum Developer

Jan 2020 - Present

Tech Elevator (Education)

Remote

Wrote and peer reviewed new developer "boot camp" curriculum material - tutorial programming exercises, student book content, and instructor lecture notes.

Collaborated with other curriculum developers and instructors on sprint planning, material feedback, and instruction styles.

Tech: Vue.js, HTML, CSS, Markdown, Bitbucket, Asana

Web Developer

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

Bry's Marine (Marine Sales/Service)

Remote

Rebuilt and redesigned website on lightweight CMS with focus on SEO and better user experience.

Site: www.brysmarine.com

Tech: Grav CMS, PHP/Twig, jQuery, HTML/CSS/JS, DreamHost, Cloudinary

Software Engineer/Lead Software Engineer

Traffic Safety Store (Traffic Safety/E-commerce)

Remote/Philadelphia, PA

Developed interactive sign designer that shows live preview as customer types and changes font size, color, and positioning. Resulted in more than \$36,000 of additional sales in first 6 months.

www.trafficsafetystore.com/product/customization?productoptionid=4625

Doubled sales of vinyl roll-up signs by implementing new stylish interface with built-in search that brings the most relevant signs to the top, and supporting hundreds of different sign legends.

www.trafficsafetystore.com/traffic-signs/roll-up-48

Increased conversion rates of safety vests by 20% with enhanced site search and filtering capabilities that gave customers the ability to find products by size, color, material, and ANSI safety rating quickly.

www.trafficsafetystore.com/safety-vests

Created new admin interface achieving goals of unified login across all sites, better visibility into e-commerce & phone orders, and toggling on-sale/out-of-stock quickly for multiple products.

Sites: trafficsafetystore.com, parkingblock.com, trafficcones.com, airportsafetystore.com

Tech: ASP.NET (C# MVC), React, iQuery, HTML/CSS/JS, MS SQL Server, SSRS, Elasticsearch, Cloudinary

IT Applications Developer

Jan 2011 - Jul 2016

Dechert LLP (Litigation & Transactional Law)

Philadelphia, PA

Boosted efficiency of General Counsel team saving over 10 hours/week with system to record ethical screens, manage access lists, and automatically secure digital documents & workspaces.

Saved firm over \$20,000/year with internal skills & experience tracking application. Developed dynamic and interactive front end based on Photoshop mockups designed by marketing department.

Created custom interfaces using Okta & Box REST APIs to enable more customer service functions to be done by the Help Desk and IT Operations groups. Resulted in less customer frustration and downtime.

Tech: ASP.NET (VB Web Forms, C# MVC), jQuery, HTML/CSS/JS, MS SQL Server, SSRS, SSIS, iManage

Jul 2016 - Sep 2019

Associate Software Engineer

Coventry First (Life Insurance Settlement)

Feb 2010 - Jan 2011 Fort Washington, PA

Increased productivity of Contract Analysis department by enhancing key system, enabling more data to be captured and tasks done more efficiently. Analyst daily calls increased 10-20% and significantly reduced backlog.

Designed new system for annual maintenance review workflow with new approval request form and ability to track approval history. Decreased complexity of process, made less error prone, and less frustrating to the users.

Tech: ASP.NET (VB Web Forms), VB.NET WinForms, HTML/CSS/JS, MS SQL Server

Applications Developer

Jan 2007 - Feb 2010

Capmark Financial Group, Inc. (Commercial Mortgage)

Horsham, PA

Upgraded major finance application to ASP.NET 2.0 and implemented new features from business requests. Worked with QA department to ensure full coverage of testing and an error-free release.

ASP.NET Developer

Jun 2006 - Jan 2007

School of Tourism & Hospitality Management, Temple University (Education)

Philadelphia, PA

Created ASP.NET web applications to demonstrate improved business methods for professionals in hospitality management, event planning, and risk prevention.

OTHER TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

PhilaGeek 2013 - 2014

Developed iOS app for configuring routers running third-party firmware DD-WRT.

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dd-wrt-mobile/id837907894

Bry's Marine 2010 - 2014

Developed custom interface for transmitting store inventory to manufacturer database searchable by all North American marine dealers. Part sales increased 10% helping clear out older and obsolete parts.

Rewrote text-based custom inventory program as WinForms application for use on Windows 7.

EDUCATION

Temple University College of Science & Technology

2007

Bachelor of Science, Information Science & Technology / Business Administration, magna cum laude

High Technology High School Web Development & Programming Track

2002

School named a "Star School" by NJ Department of Education, recipient of National Blue Ribbon Award, and consistently ranked within the top 20 high schools of New Jersey & US by many news organizations.

VOLUNTEER

International Student Volunteers - Australia

2004

Eagle Scout Award - Boy Scouts of America

2002